LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

ChrisWarren

Software Engineer

ABOUT ME

I'm a **passionate developer** that has been passionate about learning **new technologies** for a very long time. I've been a **mentor**, a **coach**, & **many other things** during my lifetime & career. I've developed for desktop, web, & native mobile environments, as well as cross-platform environments.

EXPERIENCE

SwagCheck, Inc. United States (**Remote**)

React Native Developer

December 2021 - January 2022

My responsibilities included developing the SwagCheck app using multiple technologies including React Native.

Avaaz Media, Inc. United States (Remote)

Full-Stack Developer (WordPress)

December 2020 - February 2021

My responsibilities included developing the website for The Brown Geeks and helping to convert the website from WordPress (PHP) to React.js

St. Matthew's Churches, United States (Westlake, TX)

Web Designer Network Administrator/Security Desktop Software Engineer

July 2010 - November 2012

I was responsible for building the company's website (both intranet and internet), LAN & WAN using various technologies such as **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **C#**, & **Java**. While with them, I wore many hats in a company of 7 people.

TOOLS

- Android Studio
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Visual Studio Code

SOFT-SKILLS

- Communication
- Team Building
- Team Management
- Project Management
- Mentoring
- Teaching
- Motivation

LANGUAGES

- Django[®]
- HTML
- Java (Android®Development)
- Kotlin[®] (Android[®] Development)
- Python[®]
- React[®]
- React Native[®]

Freelance, United States (Various) Solution Engineer

January 2007 - Present

My responsibilities have included:

- Implementing Desktop, Mobile, & Web services
- Using technologies such as
 - Objective-C (for iOS devices)
 - o SWIFT
 - Java (For Android®)
 - Kotlin[®]
 - JavaScript
 - TypeScript
 - React[®]
 - React Native[®]
 - o MySQL
 - PostgreSQL[®]
 - Firebase[®]
 - AWS

United States Navy, United States (**San Diego, CA**) *Information Systems Technician (IT2)* 2nd Class

July 1999 - December 2006

While an active member of the **United States Navy**, I served with distinction.

TECHNOLOGIES

- Bootstrap
- CSS
- Firebase
- Git
- Node.js
- PHP
- JavaScript
- REST APIs
- SASS
- SQL
- Tailwind
- TypeScript
- Unit Testing

OPERATING SYSTEMS (OSs)

- Linux
- macOS[®]
- Windows®

EDUCATION

Kenzie Academy

Indianapolis, IN (**Remote**) Certificate Front-End Web Development & Full-Stack Web Development

October 2019 - October 2020

San Diego State University San Diego, CA (Correspondence)

Computer Science Bachelor's Degree

August 2000 - June 2003

San Diego State University San Diego, CA (Correspondence)

Computer Science Master's Degree

August 2003 - June 2006

Open-Source Contributions

- KDE (Remote)
- Kubuntu (Remote)

OTHER CERTIFICATES I'VE RECEIVED

- <u>Responsive Web Design</u> September 2019
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures October 2019

freeCodeCamp.org

- Front-End Libraries
 February 2020
- <u>Data Visualization</u> June 2020
- <u>Scientific Computing</u>
 <u>with Python</u>
 July 2020